Good morning. How's everyone doing tonight?
People I told you I told you I was gonna be back I told you I was gonna be back in the morning
Mmm, guess what? I'm back in the morning. Wait right here. I'll be back in the morning
Bull listen to that song. I don't feel how we start off for how far spring
Amata
There's Washington Jersey Shore family vacation last night that's pretty awful
Pretty good, we got some pull requests
Shoutout Wilfred and faux ham
First making some poor requests
Great. Love to see you guys contributing touch. Laughs of course is MIT license
So anything you'd like to ask me bugs you'd like to fix we certainly welcome us. I think we now have
Smoking my weed. I think it's funny. She opened up to me get comfortable with me once I got at Tommen
I loved her she loved me. I know that I'm nothing like some other family
They want me to be if I find a way would you walk it with me?
Look at my face while you're talking to me cuz we'd only have one conversation a week. Can I get one?
conversation at least
Shout out to everyone making my beats you helping me preach the music's the only thing keeping it at peace when I fall into pieces
All of the stars have a reason a reason
We'll go back to talking in a minute I'm those rogues of shit, bro
All right, let's go back to working so what I say, we're gonna write today we write the test set
So
to go here
It starts out when it starts slamming now
I don't know if these poses are actually in the right place, but fortunately we have ground truth for this
Send videos around please
Driver X Y Z just make that another parameter you passed in
Why not do anything they don't like to cope so
Because look at the top here
Like this isn't this isn't started zero zero
It starts with some weird coordinate frames so you have to deal with that
And we're gonna have to deal with the fact that oh man let's go
Have that much space is that good? No, I'm smoking weed this morning. It is a work day
Well, let's go
We'll pass in the actual pose to process frame that's a little day
Happy Wednesday
Hello
It's probably like a one-liner to read this. Yeah, we have work to do get their
Map float across
Sorry about anybody who liked SSA format this is wrong
Never get it right map object. No, I was actually lon
List comp plan job
Map
Lambda X
Map flow fine. I don't know why I guess I won't use a list comprehension
Map object. No, I want to run math. I was just some Python 3 bullshit that I don't know
This is too like lazy evaluation or something
Just did - 3 lazily evaluate maths or something I
Filtered that oh
Very cool now, I can India way that we got to do work before we do work. You know, it's like pre-gaming
Okay, so those are the quick turning ons
Now we're going to need to write some code to go from quaternions to matrices
Yeah, let's do that
There's gonna be a library that does this pi quaternion old shitty
Normal
So quick turn on is another way to
Represent
This looks pretty good. There we go. Perfect just copy out. What's the license on us?
There's a license
It's kind of that's kind of
Me
I'll see what these things do if n is less than underscore ETS
Epsilon for testing with a number close to zero doesn't seem important. Oh
And this isn't vectorized you have to vectorize this I'm doing pretty well
Okay, I definitely need to make a stupid copy
Don't I outer that's interesting
Why don't why are they doing math at square root and on numpy square I
Went and this is doing to watch man
Your eyes gonna vectorize this I'm saying
It right
Capital R. Which is some matrix from helpers and port
Turn their matches without the other store gotta work
Local variable Q reference before assignment. Oh
Shit that I copied
You know lot scrap
Index too is out of bounds for access with size one
No, I gotta put my parentheses those are very important
Okay, well seems to do nothing the Nikes vectorize correctly
It seems like it works
MP vector ice to find a function which takes a nested sequence of
It takes a single or tuple
Well, let's just write the stupid way for the hell and then maybe somebody can fix this later on a pull request
Well, we all right cool
Right, it's not
See what I just wrote I should feel ashamed or whatever. Oh it was terrible
Their tabs tabs are the bane of my existence. I hate tabs
Okay, cool now that works I don't know why vectorize doesn't work somebody who actually liked those things can probably make that work
But that's some ugly-ass Co right there so, you know
I'm thinking about the language, you know the kind of language. Is that like?
And pose Artie is also not a vectorized thing
Well do it 9000
Kind of copying clothes are 2 years kind of shitty
It's in call and in parentheses, oh, wow clearly, it's important that I do this
Where's
Okay, so few things
Think what we want to do
Is say MP
went out in GT o sub 0
P
Mo's
Work work maybe. Yeah looks pretty good
Cool so theoretically those should be poses
Think is like I don't know if that's actually correct with the rotations
I'm not sure like
I've always been kind of confused about which is applied. First is the rotation applied first or is the translation apply first
This looks wrong
Let's let's look in the actual ground truth. See what it is
We know that the first thing it does is moves on the z axis
So
Yeah, that looks like it's just pretty much moving on the Z why is that showing a bit of movement on the Y
That doesn't seem right
So therefore what we might want to do is you don't want to uh, apply the rotation separately we want to do it like this
Right back on what we had
So it is the other way then we're just gonna be yes, I
Mean that's so moving a lot on the x-axis, but at least it's not moving on the y-axis
Try this
It's still moving on the x-axis take a look so these are the that movement
I'm not sure. That's really when you look at it actually slam
We're gonna have actually slam it looks like it only moves on that access
So let's try this. Maybe we have to uh, apply the rotation from the translation
Well, try that first see like the order matters, right
Shapes are not aligned for all align my shapes brow
Closed transpose
There we go, all right now it's moving in the y-axis this is worse
Like I don't know what to do, right
By that first
And we would expect movement really only on the z-axis so that's identical
Which that doesn't seem like it should be like that at all
That's identical to that
Different from this we don't undertake the translation, but you see how this is like messed up like this
Hashtag Andy. Hi Bros. It's bad boy
My first time frames it just comes forward in the Z location I might be wrong about this
Pose
So
There's the pose yeah, so notice how we're moving almost exclusively in the z axis
Remember everything about this is up to slam
It's up to scale
It says we're moving forward in the z axis, which is actually wrong
And that's because what we really want to do is you want to invert the policy
But yeah, so it's moving almost exclusively the z-axis so in order whatever this ground truth is it better be exclusively easy
All right Burke XYZ, I got the right thing that's not happening
Three the website there, there's some information about it. Yeah
How did they get the ground truth where does the ground truth come from wait does grant trees come from
More info
The Kinect was pointed typical. It's a Kinect the sequence contains only translational motion
As it is very simple ground truth the trajectory
So that's what we did
Yeah, here we go
So clearly we have to rotate it back
Like let's just play with the rotation first to get back to the track, I'm sorry the translation first, let's get that to be correct
We should be able to do this without dealing with the rotation
Okay, so that's clearly wrong
You can even like sample
It is moving along this axis, but there's first off there's a huge offset
You're coding up AI to save me bro, I think what I'm doing
It's not right? Okay. What if we switch the order of those does that matter? How does that not matter?
Like it's literally the same but how does it make sense
I'm still printing the shape of something stupid aren't I? Yeah
Okay
I
Think I see the problem this is XY and Z and
The movement according to my experiments should be almost exclusively in the z axis. It's not I
Didn't like read it wrong right Dax to ITV and I did from zero to full our that's right
They did from full onward and that's the quick turn IANA
rotation
I mean it's possible
But this is wrong or oh, I know it's possible
Well, maybe you don't actually want to invert this
Maybe like they encode it weird like that
Okay, well that's showing no motion in the z-axis, which is interesting because it's the only place that we have
That's worse great
See if they talk more about like how the pose is oh
Let's check them right intrinsic promise, correct
Yeah, it's like half is fine
That's normalizing this stuff, ah, here we go
Okay
Gives the position of the optical center of the color camera with respect to the world origin as defined by the I
Got a so Leopold's mechanical. I know this is what a lot of livestream coding devolves into
It devolves into kind of bullshit where people talk about like key boys and set up some stuff
Okay, well first off, let's are the timestamps vaguely sorted
So I can make sure I'm not doing anything stupid back
If they're very sorta
gives the
orientation of the optical center of the color camera in form of a
Unit quaternion on with respect to the world origin as defined by the motion capture system
Okay, so I think we're first gonna want to rotate the world
We're gonna want to uh, apply this rotation
Wait, this isn't necessarily correct
Orientation with respect to the motion capture system
So we want to move everything into the orientation of the camera
This stuff is really hard
Okay, so here here's this time of motion capture system, here's the camera facing this way right
so what we want to do is
Move things into the perspective of the camera. How do we do it?
Basically this is the new origin
So we can certainly subtract that
Noir here, but we're still rotated like this. So now I think we rotate
That isn't right
No, okay, we shouldn't just be trying things I'm so bad about this
My mammals aren't wrong, right
GG r equals quarter neon matrix. Yeah, it's fun. I
Don't like typos this right?
Wait a second, is that even a rotation matrix? That's a weird-ass rotation matrix?
That function broken I really hope that functions are not broken
MP dot t-- q q x MP square, let's just double check that
Like turning on to rotation matrix, yeah, I'm aware I'm aware
Well, you show me a better way to do it
Once I know the answer it might be helpful, but
Okay, two
Units
Multiply that shit I
Don't know there's a way to check or something as a valid rotation so we could do a 3d on that
Yeah, okay, so I'm trying oh
Okay, so the middles are one so that's a good
these these these eigenvalues are one so if the
X okay, so that seems okay
So here's the here's the cent here's the here's the
Camera, and here's like two poses, right?
So here's pose of campus zero here's post camera, so we want to rotate everything into this coordinate frame
This rotation is defined with respect to yes
It looks like they all change
So that makes sense
So if I subtract that out it's like I'm moving this to here
Now when I go like I
Just want to apply the rotation right I
Tried that and
That's not correct
Let's take a look at their script they have some evaluation scripture here. That'll teach me something
That are automatic evaluation - let's see what they have to evaluation
Comparison we offer a setup
Evaluate absolute trajectory
Align it using the time stamps. Oh, are we not
For these time stamps, not at all matching the camera time stamps. Is that the problem?
Because this just sampled in a totally different
Because I threw a lot of stuff away
They sort of explain everything but oh
Yeah, these are just totally in the wrong time basis, oh wait these don't even line up at all. Oh
Okay
Yeah, okay fine. Oh
That's annoying
Okay Wow
You see the problem
Like these time stamps are just unrelated
Ah stupid stupid stupid stupid it's stupid
Yeah, so if you guys saw on the other stream I encoded these things in like videos so they were reasonable to work with
But that threw away
The timing information
So they actually started the capture before they started the video. I got you
Knew they were trying to scam me bro. Trying to scam me this free dataset was trying to scam
That's why we should have paid IDM for a data set
The data set we paid for
Amazing kitty I'm using Fryeburg. I'm sure if we had paid IBM for a data set. It would have been the highest quality data set
That's right
That's not floats
I
Gotta get your parsing of good man. You learn this shit and CTFs real fast
All right now now let's see what's up
Okay now welcome to another stupid thing
where
We're gonna run into a problem because you can't interpolate quaternions nicely. Oh
Wow, I'm not a text that you know what that sounds like that sounds like a Python 3 problem
No, that's right. That's my fault. Never mind. I'm sorry for blaming Python 3
Okay, so we're gonna want to do NP internal
1 dimensional linear interpolation so we don't want it to be one-dimensional. We want a multi-dimensional CyHi enter
See the problem. Well, I
Was gonna play some cardi B, but I'll totally get a copyright strike for that
So we want to say Gigi's 0g cheese
Ii of work
It's gonna complain that
Like well you have to do it in order. Otherwise, it doesn't work
Yeah object to deep for desired or a man
With deep desire right deep inter these are like helper functions we have it comma
Um
Let's look at sigh pi interpolate maybe sci-fi interpret it has a deep interpolate we got a deep interpolate. Oh
Oh, wow I could do
oh, look at all these interpolators Wow, and none of them probably do what I want because it's I PI o
multivariate interpolation Wow
Interpolate a 1d function like this is bullshit
Interpolate over a 2d grid. I don't want to D. You guys know what I want to write right? I
Just want to broadcast it, you know
Fine
Eg P equals NP 0 is
running shave
Sub 0 comma 3 + 4
y + 3 + 4
Z TP sub I come with that thingy
+ I oh
They're not of the same length now you tell me all this in length
Oh, well, you know we got to make sure that that that's very important. The Boscombe is very important. Oh great
Not broadcast arrived. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, how do I want to do this? Someone put a colon here?
No, right
Finally, we're in the right. We're in the right bullshit. Don't get the bullshit twister kids
Get the bullshit twisted. You're gonna have a bad time. Let's call this one GDP in this one GT
Gonna have a bad dirt it out stop right now
Well, well index theories out of bounds of size 300, of course, yeah that makes a lot of sense of tight right now
I love it. Yeah, thank you. Well, thank you for being so you. Oh also Stu one claw solicitor one pasta
All right
Something
Okay, now let's just try the first thing we tried that's probably the right thing
Wasn't the right thing
Maybe it was and I'm just like going to hard
Times yeah, it's not the right thing seem kind of right though
Yeah, I know I'm trying things but like at least like, you know
Okay
Okay, why don't I think this was better
Commit a little something
Okay, but at least that's fixed now we can think more about other things
Probably what we want to do is we want to do that first. That's just if we rotated back and we ignore the
That moves it all on the y-axis, which I know is not right
With my interpolation shit, correct, we're reading that
We're like 100
To 1 or 2 why did I think this was better?
It does seem to just move back on this like here it just seems to move on the Z oh
No, it's actually moving on the X as well
Moving on the X as well
Hmm
Yeah, I'm using numpy interrupts the primers only works with a one-dimensional function not a two dimensional function
Well, there's plenty more work to do on trips while of course guys who said we're done
Well, we're so today what we're adding in is we're adding in
Basically ground truth
We want to see how each line actually works for the drive tests
And then we're gonna stand up a Jenkins shit so we can actually run the tests a lot
Already wrote it
Okay, so look we're moving along the z-axis and you can see that right here
Like the movement along the z-axis is like five times larger the movement along any other access
You have very small rotations and it moves straight on the z-axis up to like frame 40
So we should know that all the way to 40
It's obviously correct I can see
But this saying that it's moving equally as much on the x axis as the z axis, that's not right that's
Because we're still in the rotation frame of the
Snow/icy I don't understand I don't know whether they applied the rotation first or the translation first
So probably what we're going to want to do is we're gonna wanna maybe we do have to do the applying on a fly thing
What you think about remove print from terminal print use a lot of resource
Well, you put it like that
Push it ban print everywhere
Especially in the media banned the media no
Bro order of translation and relation for matrix interpolation, bro
Alright
Let's check to make sure we don't do anything student at first of all, it's print GT
It should be just be
Yeah, it seems pretty right
So these are the translation ones
Alright, you know what? I hate. I hate when numpy prints with that kind of shit
so let's just do it's like numpy dot set print pop and
Suppress equals true and it won't print in floating-point
Bullshit anymore. It'll print it like human readable
Something else that I'm not surprised equals true
No, they see like I don't want it in floating-point, okay. Well, maybe it's just maybe I just can't because
Some of them are too big. Yeah. Okay, I
Won't put that up here. Anyways a useful thing to have
Okay, so this is the translation these are the quaternions for rotation
Now there's a little bit of bullshit, but I don't think it matters
We should really renormalize our quarter neon
So we can do this here and NP now
It's not opposed to that cutter neon thing being broken either
But yeah, so when you do an interpolate on a quaternion
You have to renormalize it because the sum of a concerning out has to be one
so let's just say GT sub or
Well, I give zero shits about Google reCAPTCHA, some people really don't know what a joke is
Whoever followed that and liked that thing really like missed the joke
Okay, now my cranium is normalize I
Don't know it's possible that this doesn't work. I
Did check to make sure they were valid rotation matrices
By doing an s-video
SC now it's not a valid rotation matrix
You can see these eigenvalues or whatever. These things are whatever the middle of SVD is is not ones
So you do need that
So now there was and now I'm happy, okay
It's still not having
Here's the thing here's the position
So the rotation as it translates, it's definitely gonna rotate
So there is a right way to do this and we just need to think
Yeah
Let's even you're missed you weren't here for a pull request our oh
You don't I could use like he's a piece of paper. That would certainly help a bro out. Hey
Okay, I mean I think we want to apply the rotation first
Right like here we are
Let's apply the rotations to the rotations
So now yeah, we've applied the rotations to the rotations so we've rotated the whole leg, okay. So here here's that here's the UM
here's the here the the the
Capture device here's this and we've rotated it all like whoof, right and that's like whoa, great
But now each one of those rotations is
Like we've pointed the first thing correctly now after we do that
we can subtract out the translation -
And then we've moved that no no no no we can't we can't because
The rotation I believe still depends on the translation, right
Apply the rotations of the Clifford
Yeah, I need a needle board
Okay, so now we've applied the rotations to themselves I
Don't know if we can subtract I still don't think we can subtract out the
Like this is probably a really obvious thing if I just like to think a little bit better
We've applied the rotations to that now we're gonna have to I think we definitely want to apply the rotations
Do we
Yeah, let's uh
I'll picture in a paint program
Okay online paint
Oh
Okay, let's try
Try online
No, this is so hard. Oh, I need flash plugin, Oh what j/s paint that it?
Dead what what is this? Crap? Google sucks
Okay
So here's the capture device and here's
Here's a frame and here's a frame
Okay, so the rotation and the translation are with respect to the capture device frame
So
Let's let's this is this is pretty good we've got we have I paint an online painting program
It's like MS paint, which is exactly what I wanted cool
So we have to think about how to get this to be in the coordinate frame of the first camera
so this is the coordinate frame wherein maybe this was like an arrow pointing this way and
We have to get to this coordinate frame
So you see how like translation rotation are intertwined right now
Let's think about what we have to do I'm rich that's true
But I don't have paper because it's old we draw another frame over here
One frame to frame three five
Like hmm, okay. You see why the first thing we don't really want to rotate the world is the first thing
Yeah, I know
We don't really want to rotate the world of the first thing because rotating the world will just rotate you around this Center
Let's think if we move the center from here to here
Does that matter?
Like other rotations still correct. This rotation is still going to be correct, but these rotations
Well, see that's the thing I don't really know right
Which is applied first the rotation or the translation
Does it tell me
Give us the position of the optical center of the color camera with respect to the world origins defined by the rotate as the motion
Capture system. Okay, so that seems pretty obvious to me
It's it's the rotation that's confusing
So it does seem like the first thing I do is the fact that the translation that's what is that gonna work
It really depends on which is applied first, but no no that might be okay
So now that if I if I subtract out the translation I get a new color does have colors. Oh
No, I want colors
Their colors over here or colors all perfect
okay, so if I subtract out the translation
With my current understanding of it. It's just gonna move
No
I'm gonna delete this
It's gonna move this to here
That's what subtracting out the translation should do right
So if I subtract out the translation should just do that
And then I can't really understand right, maybe I want to deploy
Each rotation
Okay
Tried D. Applying the whole rotation
But that's clearly not right? Okay. So what I tried to do there was just D apply this big rotation
But I don't think that's right
We can t applying the rotation from each translation
And that should disentangle, oh no, no no no we don't have to do that. There should be one rotation gets us back
But see that's weird because at least now all the movement is a long one axis, it's just the y axis so
That just has like a fixed offset wrong subtract out the translation D apply the rotation from each translation
Do you actually mean that is that is that a serious suggestion
Here the rotations
So they clearly change
Let's do you ply the rotations from the rotations start with that
So it's clearly rotating
Which I mean it makes sense, right? It makes sense in the perspective of this thing is moving
But like what doesn't make sense is why
The translations aren't correct when I do this
That should make the translations, correct
But dust they're wrong oh
We will we'll wait
gives the orientation of the optical centre of
The colour camera with respect to world origin. Aha. So what that actually is is
This rotation is what it's giving me
So, whoops
I have a blue blue, please
Can I can I have a blue? Yep. Yep. Oh, I got a press okay
I see that I see what your brows were saying. Okay, so that's that rotation
Here's the position of the optical centre with respect to the world origin
Okay, so that's the position of the Alpha done with respect world origin
That rotation here tells me how to rotate that
- look at - but
Then I still don't understand. Why what I said was wrong, right?
So if I just subtract out that and rotate them all based on the first one
That seems like it should be correct I
Don't really understand it
I'll be back
The orientation
The optical center with respect to world orientation transpose first, okay
So inverse is the same thing as transpose for a rotation matrix
Tan inverse they say I do that
Well
That's actually spookily the same
Which makes sense from D applying like one rotation, right
Position in the optical center of the color camera with respects the world origin is defined by the motion captionist
The orientation of the optical center of the color camera in the former unicorn with respect to the world origin
But see like that's right
Oh
Okay, here's my theory now
My theory is that this one is correct
But the axes just don't correspond
Yeah
Well, there's no there's no reason the axes have to correspond right I
Wish they included like a little like picture for explain things, but I mean
If you think about it, right we don't know what the motion capture system
We don't know how the motion captured the system defines the
Defines the world
But otherwise those look correct right except for the fact that the axes are messed up
Like the motion capture system might define the world in some weird frame
Let's see which one that matches because I think we can actually do this now
Yeah, so this is the one that's increasing a tiny bit
There's a negative one
There's a negative one there's a small negative one. Wait, does that like change a lot?
Wow, it's like different for initialization. That's the highest quality shit now
There's like a small negative one a slightly larger positive one and a big positive one. So
If I look here there's a small negative one, there's a slightly larger positive one and is it okay?
Yeah, you found marybelle script. Let's take a look
Maybe they talk about it in here. Oh
Hey, look it's he exists
So they're putting the translation in there I
Know they're doing we thought they have the ugliest interpolation you've ever seen
The rotations a long trajectory
Yeah, well I mean we can see what it is now, right, so the problem is just that these things are in the wrong order
Until we have to also do a transposition
The key T
Equals GG t 1 to 0
About 1 to 0
We want to
First pick the small negative 1 so it's 2 0
There we go, those should match pretty closely now
High-quality, holy shit guys, ok
Well, so that's actually a rotation that we can apply
We can we can just talk about that rotation
Orient
Python
Like an orient library
Or is that just that just might be built in Tacoma
So that that rotation can actually be done okay, so if we have the
y-axis
And we want to become the z-axis. We want the z-axis to become the x-axis. We gotta do that
No, no, it's just annoying
But the reason we have to do it in a rotation matrix is so we can apply the same thing to the rotation
All right
We want to be yes, we just want to do with our rotation matrix I
Think the matrix actually wait, I can define that matrix very easily
So if I want to to go with 0 is just 1 1 0 1
1 0 0 0 1 1
We'll call this
Camera frame
Okay, so effectively what I did is just to find that as a matrix where we can apply that same matrix to the rotations
Well, that's at least ground truth for translation, let's get country through everything
So for the rotations, let's go back to our paint, bro
Rotation was gonna be a little bit trickier. Oh
Wait, they just talked about the optical center with respect to the the origin. So just uh apply the first rotation
Actually might be all we need to do I only need to certainly apply this as well camera frame from capture
That's not even right
All right first
Yeah, it's probably more right, okay cool
Well put it this way let's do that first then we shouldn't leave that
Yeah, cool, so we'll just apply that to the rotation really candy apply the first rotation
We have to do apply it after we apply it the translation, um well
If that's the case, let's go back to you making this simpler. Let's try this thing
Ideally I would like to do it like this
Okay, that's pretty good I
Don't actually know if the rotations are correct
Maybe we'll find out sooner rather than later when we actually had to put these things in just slam
By
Sounds good
Brings poses it
Gggg, oh I'll say
Well, so we actually don't want to just do polls because that's in the wrong
You guys enjoyed it
High quality shit
That's the multiplier
Kind of wrong
50 is like the stylus winding
Broke em
Well, so the thing is poses then we want to pose optimization anymore. I
Don't know why it like okay, it just moves them back to their
Attack it for now to fix the pose. You know, what?
Okay, well this is where this is where things go if you just trust a graduate
Of course everything becomes kind of bullshit but
My rotations might be wrong
But that's the graduate of the data set
My rotation throw
Or am I like let's take a look and say we actually I'm moving that way that's good
So the translations are definitely correct, I just don't know about the rotations
Okay, it works so poorly I
Know it's cool. We can just put this here
That stuff doesn't hurt we can actually add in observations before we get a pose
Okay, so that keeps doing that probably cuz my rotations are wrong
Let's try the rotation dataset, let's see if we get the rotations to be right
And then I'm gonna go I have about twenty minutes more with you guys you know how this goes
Yeah, okay. So the rotations are just totally bogus
Well, that's good
Let's go back to trying to debug that so we know the first thing that happens is a rotation in that direction
Okay, so that's the cb2 Rodrigues function let's try that
Right here
Previous so what cv2 Rodriguez does is it just felt right?
It's just gonna print out like the Euler angles
Prints out the Euler angles. It's very hard to like see whatever paper maybe says
Of course. Yes, of course. That's no I need my parentheses because this is Python 3 7 most people. All right
So those are clearly wrong like we know what's happening here. We know how it's rotating and it's not working like that
Okay
So ok standing argument that we have to do that because I that's why I do the translation
That's alright
We know the first thing that happens is a rotation like this
So let's first confirm that there's actually no translation in this data set
Yeah, that's pretty much about translation is that
We multiplying it by 20, where's x over there, well, that's actually some kind of translation
Makes me think we could be wrong again
Do you think what we actually might want to do is apply each rotation
That some translation -
If we didn't really think this through we just kind of typed
This is so shitty I
Don't really know how to debug this I
Just know that that well that's actually right but only because our optimizer so powerful. Oh
My gos we're not saying GG post, yeah
Like that's saying that it's translating right there's clear translation there which is wrong
Mm
Okay, okay, okay. Okay. Okay. Let's look at this
I'm speaking of map box locate later than that by the way familes going to be there
So interesting so they have a they're showing their registration translation here I think
Yeah, there's a translation here and there shouldn't be because there's no translation
No, wait, there's no translation
Where does it make sense because
Yeah, that's yeah no no is that translation
Set an appreciable amount of translation
Do I have to uh, apply each rotation as the question
Do I have to uh, apply the rotations before I subtract out the org
Tomorrow we're gonna get paper and we're gonna try this with paper. Yeah, Bruce
That's like way more off
It's still saying this translation the old Jill hot is dead kill him
Do that hey, that's the problem
That translation is translate I
Shouldn't be translation. I still think so
It sure looks like there's no translation I
Don't get it. I mean, this is very clear about saying
With respect to the world origin is defined by the motion capture system. That's very clear
It holds our reverse I searched the store today
Okay, let's put it back to the thing that we know works for that
So that works for that and the only thing we don't know is what we have to do for rotation
The thing is almost anything will work for this one
You know, they're all messed up wait, hang on not almost anything will work that's just completely wrong
I mean now that are like subtleties and in correctness
Maybe we need to invert them
See it's showing translation that's translation that I don't really believe
But the rotation is completely wrong I'm gonna sound like rotation and translation are are intertwined
What the optimizer says it is it puts them down here
Scale to have sworn enemy of binocular Slammers everywhere
No, but like the rotations are wrong and that's why this is messing up you see them they're not right I
Can really want no border matters on these things
Yeah, you see why that one has to go first, right
It's really wrong with the rotation
All right guys I gotta go to work
See clearly my rotations are wrong we're gonna think this through later
This is at least right
In the presence of small rotation
Let's just make sure the things work and I don't submit any ground truth is cuz I wrote
But let's make sure the good example still works
For some initialization bug cool. All right guys, I'm gonna commit this
Let's give a prize to
Anybody who can actually if somebody can fix this we'll give you a price. I
Don't know what the price will be. But you know me. I'll be back on streaming the same hours tomorrow
Because like Logan Paul Jake Paul say, it's everyday bro. I
Think I think it's everyday bro is really a really inspirational
Thing like you know this everyday bro, like it's just it's inspirational because it is everyday
Like that's a really yeah great. Thank you guys. Let's commit so we'll call it broken ass ground treat aspect
Broken ass round through testing of matrix is hard
The yo, what can I slow the foam that I want fixed again, so if you go in here
This is clearly not the right ground truth for this for this video
Look at how look at how it says that the camera is rotating like an D it like that right? So
it's because the way I'm extracting the ground truth is wrong just
Like I have my like order of my matrix multiplies wrong or something
So you can check out down here it's one of these
That's wrong. So that's what I want fixed
But yeah, good luck with that shit guys I
Am out I will see y'all
Tomorrow same time
You'll see what we have today what song should we start with
High-quality
I
Do react to the chat wistful fella, bro
Yeah, subscribe to my channel
People fix these cemeteries up they're tired of seeing them banned. Okay, so where I was yesterday
And then that stuff messes up
That's supposed to be rotation it's not that's because my shits long
This stuff
So what we're trying to do is we're trying to get the
Holy Smoke just waiting activate subdue that
Ek dark sky. How do I activate subs?
Yeah, and what what sourcing the map data
Sourcing the maps
The reason I think that about FPGAs and GPUs is
You're just not gonna get that much of an improvement over GPUs, right? It's all about
It's all about how many transistors you use right
I'll look into I'll look into why nobody can subscribe after this
But it's about how many transistors are used and
GPUs are already using like 80 percent of the transistors. So maybe we can get a 20 percent boost
You're not gonna get like a huge boost
people think like the transition from
GPUs to a6 is gonna be similar to the transition from
CPUs two GPUs, and that just isn't true. This isn't like mining like if you're doing like Bitcoin mining. Yeah, you're actually huge advantages
From doing it with
Her cuz I'm tired I'm from phoom phoom switching to an ASA I just woke up. I think your friends as much astronaut really
Are you just doing the twitch affiliate program? Oh I'm gonna be an affiliate. Oh, wow, that's bullshit
Well, I like being I like being affiliated with shit
Alright, so where are we well, I
Was thinking maybe we could apply this thing globally
Let's first try this I was thinking today we try just applying shit to the pose makers
So that the whole thing is kind of like Apple I do it once
Instead of applying it just throw tation matrix because I think my translation was correct
Okay, so whatever happened there it really messes these up
She's going on. Oh, wow, that's Friday. Yes
So d applying the pose
Okay, well that's wrong
Like the code to fix translation was actually correct. I was just rotating it by this
Um, I don't need money too much money man
They can google the learned index paper
Yeah, I mean look at my cat mind makes sense for google cuz like maybe you can't even get to X
But you're not gonna get 10x is all I'm saying
Okay, it's not enough to overcome
Like code inertia. Alright, cuz they're gonna be harder to code for the GPUs
Another quarter nyan matrix, which had different values. Okay, so
According to this
This was the translation yet. That works. Let's go back to acts wisely. I could see it better there have
Some translation thing that actually worked
Yeah, so that's putting all the stuff on the z axis you can see it there Oh
Cruz are raising money
Raising money is not an accomplishment
Raising running is a sign of your weakness and they advertise it like it's a strength
We raise money. I was ashamed as you should be
It means that you haven't been probably you haven't made your company profitable you had to better
Okay, so if you D apply the rotation
Which is basically just applied no rotation then you get translation in the right sense
Let's let's look through this and we're thinking this morning, so I'm thinking
It's a position of the optical sense of the collar cam with respect to the world origin is defined by the motion capture system the
Orientation of the optical center of a color camera the value and a quarter neon respect to the world Orange
so
The translation was weird and it's questionable whether I want to apply the rotation
The transformation matrix is different my defective
Yeah, I mean Tesla should be ashamed of the money they raise to I think you on actually properly is ashamed
Hi, sorry, I'm reading this on this little on about let's go over here
Okay, so that's the same
Yeah, this is the exact same logic they just call it transform for for
The efforts and
Have that same function Oh
What is it different
Why is this different
Why did I put two two there?
Look there nothing is different from my
Say
So weird I thought the numbers are different
Let's try this thing else is the same Oh
Mike return you know, it's just weird or wrong
Yeah, okay cool well that's interesting
Good fine, bro
Yeah, now those are the correct thing and I didn't have to do any weird camera phone, okay
Wow, okay, that might have been my bug
Yeah, the values are different like that, I don't know why they're I
Don't know what could turn e on I hat. Oh
Maybe you just double use the last thing and they usually put W is the first thing
I
See
Yeah, why do they put W as the last I think that's the distinction right
T was actually off by yeah. Okay. So this old thing was assuming
Okay, there's a different ordering of the Couture yard, you see the problem good find a bra
So it's that
Knot
Which is probably a more sensible way to do it, right
Okay, cool down that bug nice job nice job, all right
So now we get with the inverse and now I think you can probably just do this Miss bobbye's gonna work
Yeah, all right bro, nice job, all right, let's have a bug cool
Turn yawns. We're out of order. And now the most obvious thing is correct
See how that works
Sometimes we get more translation, ah
They work now cool
Cool bros heroes. All right, it works
Here this is less broken
Mmm, it looks a lot better still saying this translation. Believe me if they're actually yes
Let's get rid of that times 50 right there
Are the times altogether
Yeah, cool seems a lot better
Okay, so we're not gonna sensibly get the death of anything
I mean the camera is drawing is just so massive. Just kind of wrong. Oh
I like do something stupid
Oh
The other thing I was thinking is we should probably write a grant repost processor and like put in a more reasonable format
And you ever come to my things, you know the talks probably I don't know they don't thank that I just say the same bullshit
Alright, let's commit that good job
Boston Mass. Is it bro? You're doing the price. I mean you'd win a prize if you send it a pull request
Lowest otoscope you sometimes but now we do churches so you can come on and you can see my trechie soon
Peace of all
Okay
Let's just write let's write this is a separate tool like that shouldn't really be part of a main tool
All of this creature
Thank you put that in helpers, you know to be honest
That's really used for like we just don't use return eons, so it's not really a healthy for slam I should even put this here
See like now we just have this the same thing
Okay, so we have like that NPV file, why doesn't alright love this
AR zero with a stupid name
Why is it a stupid name?
It's not possible if I don't know the names of the arrays
Those oh
Yeah, I don't give a shit about the past gross
Forget the past there is only the future
Hoes not filing the archive but what I called it pose first and
ARR zero, they didn't call it our zero
Didn't call it a RZR. Why does it do that? I
Called it posed. It doesn't make sense. I raise just saving the file a raise will be saved in a file with the keyboard names
Humans a race to save the file a race will be saved in the file with the keyword names
And it has the name pose I don't want to
Go now if I don't pass that down I should learn my Emacs
Um, if you're downloading my videos you're violating my copyright
You know, I care very deeply intellectual property and I'll sue all of you sue people
What a morning man, what a morning welcome to Thursday yeah a date tonight we're kind of excited about that
That's kind of exciting
What else is exciting
But the Groucho Marx doesn't so exciting
Ok, so we have a little problem with this the scale very interesting
Thing
Put this down back there now anything that works zero
Okay, so now that's it a normal scale factor, let's just try for a second not optimizing the pose at all
You can turn that off and point out and
Everywhere we add frame
Segmentation faults
If that's concerning yeah optimizer can't run if I tell it it can't move the frames
What's seg faulting
Optimized
Ground truth proposed
Weird
This you back bro
Its Weiss a segfault cuz someone tell me
bullshit
You're telling me I have to enable that optimize
What doesn't work?
Is that what's really happening I don't think so
Well, sure disable the optimizer and see what we get
This is just estimating the positions from now, there's some nice and smooth it looks
Alright, like this is the true camera motion. It's beautiful smooth motion
Wait out the optimal
But now's on optimizing the points and stupid points are appearing behind the camera
You don't need to have this archive stop archive the past doesn't matter
Okay, so I still understand why the sidewalls
Shouldn't be called with fixed points
Phoebe I
Don't have GED either LOD be over the logo will be be off my favorite debugger. Wait. Yeah. I can't doesn't even walk. Thanks
Thanks, ll be gay
Huh, oh it doesn't crash on the debugger except it doesn't display the bullshit
High five is disabled
So things like don't work, but that's okay I cool. What do we get? We got a null pointer
In
The optimizer
Why are we getting a null pointer?
Where are we getting where is the optimizer running?
You know segmentation fault 11
Really work up to here
And that's gonna be me that shit about all the last time oh, yeah, don't worry, okay great. Thanks. Thanks Python
But we'll add the points
It doesn't have the points it just doesn't have the
If I set them all fixed it just crashes all right
That's so stupid
Than they were fixed looks noticeably less smooth right now. Look at that frame. Why did that frame go there bad frame?
Okay
All set fix the water
Set marginalize, I don't know what this dot
The map points already set marginalize to tremendously decrease the I
Don't know any of this shit man
The bigger problem is our case in fact if I set these all to fixed it just crashes
Like how crappy is that so crappy
Why why does it do that? Why can these not be fixed?
Now that's a bug
Notice this likes to use that same weird quaternion thing where it does X Y Z W interesting, right?
That's right the past dozen I mark Hobie and shit, bro
Make a move or I don't want stupid family. If you even give it one frame to move its happy
It doesn't crash. You can't give it no frames to move because then it crashes
Okay, so these are with the ground truth poses. So this isn't slam anymore. This is just
Ma-mutt because it's doing it's doing mapping and I'm taking the poses from the ground truth
And mime up doesn't look that great. Right like my MA has all this bullshit. So we got to get rid of it
This will give us an opportunity to tune the pruner stage
You say about this I guys not a real point was that get rid of it. Yeah
Now I have to remember that I can take that back you say you see the problem I'm gonna forget
Okay less than two point match that's alt now you read that or empty me narrator five
Let's try to go to ascertain the fire
It was better
Or any points for being a cult
Call 24 points are those like higher quality points not really like my problem is why is this crap still up here?
Does it go away man, it goes away
Well, they're basically saying is every point needs to have five matches now and the error needs to be less than no
No, maybe that's actually just a really high error
Yeah, it does kind of look like a vaguely higher
And the reason he's failing is because he isn't taking a depth of the field of view what
That's AG fault, oh
Maybe we deleted all the things in the first frame
What's not having in my frame anymore I see what's going on
Then let's just say
Old point if lengthy friends five and keyframes 1 dot ID plus
10 must be detected 1/2 of x is less than
Right
So if I D plus 10 is less than
I'm gonna say that sounds good
I'll make the point color much more aggressive
Well, let the map looks better ish
We've got rid of a lot of stuff
Then I'll back to seg faulting great
Big Factory
Math looks better. So once in a while, I'll just get one where the points go everywhere. I was kind of crap
Maybe I can fix this with an earlier filter
Crash as a crash
You're now only adding in place that have a lot more information
Look for something to be a new point. It has to have very high parallax
So we're getting some of these crappy points
These are the ones that are just to have bad future deductions I
Better figure out how to add back in that check
So if I want to bring things back to local
Should be right I dot it with the pose which is sort of transformation from
I think now we're not getting any of those points behind the camera anymore
My mind went too aggressive on this
I know it looks like it's organizing into a better map
I'm just kind of going off of nap quality here. But I'm like you can't leave that crap that
Isn't good
At all this why are all these points being added to the thing
All right sure you read the arcsine paper see what or if son who's calling rules are and we get inspired
They've got all this speckle gone
Sorry real points is aren't really in the mouth and I think everything noisier for everything
Okay
Let's put that back to that rule
Too again
So now this is like optimizing the pose again and then Alice like crappy. Look, it's super crappy. Oh look at that crappy
Oh so crappy and like puts it there. Yeah
Like moves that was so crappy
Don't want use the ground truth
This is just optimizing and look look good look at shit. Look at that shit
Richland could be so much better
It's weird though, actually when I let it optimize it does a better job like the map looks better, right?
That looks like a more solid map
Then when I put in the actual ground truth poses I
Would assume that the ground treats not wrong and I was something to some other buck
Took the partial derivative of the pointed 3-space
You're seeing words but I really don't think that any of you make sense the depth of the field of view, hmm
surface of the high contrast point was this shit
So I do the Voss constant ever Tim Hecker
See my kinematic model very
So right that right it Airy that wrong
My multiply the pose the previous frame with the inverse of the pose from the frame two frames ago
And then I got that velocity is pretty good
Like the map looks better when I let it optimize pose but like that kind of looks like crap
My filtering is probably not that good. I don't read the Orson
That's why I better get rid of that added points print it spam
Window back to 20 the window the optimizer kind of toys over so it doesn't get really slow
Is this all right good check to have
And that's scale so I don't really know what to do about that a
Kinematic model just assumes constant velocity
And I said you want paper
I'm gonna stop streaming a little earlier today. I said get to work early go work to go
Mavs initialization, okay, we're doing okay about that
Features local mapping. Hmm. Ah
A representative or of descriptor D which is the Associated or descriptor whose Hamming distance is minimum
with respect to all other
associated descriptors in the key frames
Which the point is observed well, that's interesting. Okay. That's a cute way of doing it
I remember when we were talking about how to do the Hamming distance
so they just pick one that's uh
That's representative
Maximum d max and minimum diamond point in reserve according to scale variants of it's a warped features. That's interesting
Counter pose, which is a rich body transformation that transforms from the world to the camera coordinate system
Intrinsic so the origin is trying to frame so we're doing bars very similar
Lawson emotion model we're doing that. Oh
Okay, well that's interesting so they're using the velocity model and then using that for search by projection
They're doing their pose optimizer after search by projection you try that
Weird it seemed better
Well, no like it's hard to quantify better we should have it actually saved the pose then we can use the compare script I
Don't know if it's better but yeah, so that's interesting they're talking about how to do their search by rejecting
House just cuz I had graduated I know
It's messing up the first frame
No, that's the same pretty much
All right, if tracking is lost
Yeah, yeah, we don't have to worry about that track local map
If you have a point projection X in the current frame just guard if it lies outside the image
Frame, so actually that's exactly what we're doing here
Compute the angle between the current viewing ray and the map point mean viewing direction we don't do that
Compute the distance from the map point to the camera center discard of its out of the scale avarage of the map. Oh
This is interesting
Representative descriptor d of map point with still on natural features in the frame of the predicted scale in near access
So that's a search by projection. The camera pose is finally optimized with all of that points found in the frame
So we're doing a pose optimization
Only with the points
We're doing it only with the points that are matched by the brute force majeure. Oh
Here we go, they didn't - calling here
The tracking must find the point in at least 25% of the frames on which it's predicted to be visible. Wow, that's fancy
If more than one keyframe has passed from map point creation
It must be observed from at least three keyframes
Local bundle adjustment discards outlier observations, so that's exactly what we do here
Man why are discard are not good
This bug alright bugs here
I don't know. There's one a lot of error. Is that a lot? No, no, I
Don't think so. It has pixels, right?
You keep your user in pixel space. So it's the norm in pixels K. So I doesn't sound like a lot of error
Do that but
Those looking better actually, I'm really just guarding a lot of crap those crap shows up
Not really helping
Here's discarding a lot of points now, but I don't know I
Mean, maybe that's the wrong error metric as well, right?
Because if your things are moving further, you'd expect the pixel to be higher
I'm glad to jump to down there. I love it. Nice job slim
Why is it so noisy like that
Why is that frame there bad frame be more straight like go go put the other frames
With the ground
No issues
Especially disable the optimizer
Okay, look at those beautiful frames they're beautiful
That's what I want my frames to look like
Hey that velocity model works really well, I
Want my frames to look like that so good looking
Well, yeah, I mean I could add something to the optimizer to tell it not to do that but like
just have to
Like that noise as a result of noisy observations. I should just fix the observations
Look at all the inner is being discarded
It's a lot the threshold I can change
Largest functions being discarded
Okay, there's a lot of noise there but I lowered that was more discarded
No, it's pretty good
Better
Wow, that's what was making it slow though, that's cool
And see the crap showing up here now
No faster than so fast now
We are triangulating trust me
You know just making things a little faster that doesn't help
Be more like the poses
All right
Look at the high quality, you know, I have no idea that is that good cause I'm not
So I'm never using that same XYZ dataset
For one XYZ
Scale
It's impossible to see anything and all the points show up way too close
Track a single point over time. Yeah, maybe we'll do that tomorrow
Starting to chop best stuff on kitty
You know, we won't we will lower this do the next trials like very
Problem I here to talk about comma don't cut the fish lamp
It's pretty good though, maybe fast
Looking happier, though
Leave look at look at how much more straight it is here. I don't know why it's nonstop on another business
Oh, so these are getting rejected for some reason
can't understand why I
Worry that they're being rejected by that clause that I say might be broken
If you have these aren't in the map I
Had anything to nap for a while
What some?
Yeah, it would actually be pretty easy to uh
To add one on one camera. There's nothing in here that assumes one camera
Figure out that checks actually wrong
We saw points weren't getting added past a certain point
Once we got once we got a bit more around this Bend
You know, like if they have black dots like that I mean they're not being into the map for some reason that all looks good
Humans vaguely generate depth to eyes
uuugh vastly overestimate how much that matters
No, but look they're not being out of the map again, look at these points, they're not being out of the map
Why
Why have I no points here those are good matches I
Don't understand
Which check is rejecting them
Boys let's do a frame on that. Let's first see if it's a frame problem. So what if I do this C equals 200?
That work didn't work
Now
When I run the whole thing if they stop getting at it past a certain point
Even without that checks. I don't think that check is wrong
Could this check Bureau
Work with my triangulate. Oh just really not like
Thing is once the poses get large
That's a possibility
We can pretty easily just keep it read golf
Just effectively what's going
Yeah, see look these aren't getting at it anymore all those points are crap
Okay
Pose
Pose pose MP dot fun pose
In to dock pose
Elbows here
or here
Call this point low fall
Now we'll say points for D and B dot
One dot pose
That's not right because that's actually putting them in do that
Is that more correct
Yeah, I mean the question is should we triangulate them in a local we can triangulate them in a local coordinate frame
Where instead of trying in the global coordinate frame that could be the cause of these issues?
The only
Point I have against this is I don't feel that orb slim. Does it this way?
I feel like I've read the orb some code and it doesn't do it this way
But otherwise, I really have no explanation for why they should be different
Okay, I think this through a little bit more let's try this
Let's put this here and for this one
Let's solve for R T here basically
So we're going to say f1 dot pose
That isn't right
Thank you shit, man, and I don't know why I stream my streams try someone to talk to I do this
Chestnut calm you won't find it out
I'm not that good. It's not inspiring. Fuck you
Know this is fucking bullshit man. I
Hate inspiring shit inspire people to do what just go do things if you want to do things do things you'll need to be inspired
Don't care what would I do with money? I can't buy a better laptop. They don't have one yet
Can't buy faster internet. I mean, yeah, maybe it's like extremely high thing
but then I feel like
Deal with the guy digging out my street for fiber and my neighbors wouldn't like me and then I gotta just deal with things
Right, that's a lot after
your deal with things like
Okay, you know what my job is guys as manage people like I don't code at work
Manages terrible
The here I get the program I get I get the program and then in the peace and quiet of my lovely room
well drink
yerba, MA pays
It's just a nice relaxing way to start the morning I don't know today wasn't very relaxing now, I don't know why I
Feel like this is what I just wrote I
Don't know exactly the way to work
but okay, so I take the f1 pose and I remove the f2 pose and then I'm left with NPI for
All right, and then I have local points and I can get that check
And then I
Know my code is shit. I know all the
Points or D. Basically, I think I just want to apply F to pose. That's what he took out, right
Back oh
Cool alright
Let's see if the problem still happens. Oh
The points in their own place. Wow, I don't know how this works at all. It's putting all the points over there
That's just good I did something backwards
First you don't succeed like convert one of the matrixes and maybe I'll fix it
Well, let's see if the points turn black again or if they stay a good color
So we go around this turn but now these numbers are getting big right
Thank you might just be like numerical instability of the DLT. I
Swear orb slam does it the other way like I've read the code not this face. Is that ok fine
Who might argue with what works
Looks great look about beautiful. Look at that beautiful math. I love that map so nice
All right guys it's so fine points
Do in
I don't want that exits
Like an that one just it's weird
Use different sizes and colors for quaternions. I promise you are in
Pretty good
Hire you are you good do know things I
tell you the interviews for comma are basically is sit you down and I ask you questions and know things and
That if you don't know things I mean
That's okay to not know things the first time I don't like tell you something and then when I bring it up again ten minutes
Later, like no like did you learn?
It kicks my buggy code man submit a FOIA request I
Fix the bug man. What are you talking about? This isn't funny anymore. I mean there's improvements
Like we may both good bugs sure this likes
Alright we try it on Ohio. Let's try it in, Ohio
Ohio is always a great test
That's not right I just think go that way it goes the other way I stopped at battle I oh
Yeah
The wrong initialization is a common problem in the knock door slam
Yeah map, Ohio, bro
No, I don't care how old you are no one gets any special treatment I don't care
No, I came from difficult circumstances all I'm young. Oh
My dog. No, I don't care for your dog, but can you program that's what matters do you know? Thanks
This is the best I've ever seen Ohio work
What
quaternions, bro
Are you kind of music
See I don't see any quaternions on the sign though, it's that's a pretty good map of Ohio if I've ever seen one I
Found this video on YouTube. It's a video of some guy driving to, Ohio
Looks pretty good to me. Let it map Ohio for a bit more
When I hired me at 17, yeah, I probably would he's pretty good. Oh
And I wouldn't let him like code things
He's a quality shit, this is best map Ohio I've ever seen just putting that out there this is a pretty good, Ohio
Remember when we were at that Burger King with the Burger King signs right there right there it says like whopper eat whopper
More the green circles called they called it warm features
They're not good tourney opens prowl
It only gets a little slower
Switch
SiC Mapple, Ohio
Can you map in real time it's slightly Daffy far for real time. This one's almost slow down. All right stop
So uniting new points, I don't know I don't know why it slow
Yeah, it's a little slow if I tell me about flame may you know, we'll do tomorrow we'll profile
Tomorrow we'll focus entirely on speak. How about that? Sound good?
Tomorrow that's my promise to you guys. Well know we'll see what time I get home tonight
But I will try to do that tomorrow
Reconstruct surfaces from the points whatever you hear by that I have some local window, right?
Those sites like you can see it right there beautiful. Look at them traffic lights like you say went down the map
Map Ohio's like now we know we're alive great slam
So tomorrow we'll work on speed and
Then the day after that will work. We'll make the visualizer better
We'll actually have it like take some texture from the image of the stuff instead of just a point color
We're gonna make a turn a turn you'd be cool. Oh
No, maybe that's know some people in Ohio though when I was there like once I hadn't seen many people make turns
And you guys know there's only four words to so much better than other backwards
I'm not reconstructing surfaces office. So annoying little texture on the road
I'm not writing. This is feature slam. It's not that slam
No, I mean maybe we can start to add some leg maybe we can start to make it more dense
Um, but I think a focus on speed first, let's figure out why it's slow like why is it slow right now, I don't know
That's because I was probably cause it's true all I know why it's slow
It's because it's searching by projection things that are behind it
Yeah
Search by projection less
Right because we're actually searching by projection we're searching every frame
We're searching every point in the map to see if that's visible from my frame. You don't have to do that
I don't think that at all
Okay, so we can search by projection less stupidly that's gonna give us speed because like it's fast at first then it just gets slow
Okay, so we will roam file with flame
Search projection less stupidly because I think all the time right not yet is being spent on the search by projection
No, why does optimizing as always our stuff what's a big map of Ohio
Do you guys remember how this used to work remember how bad it used to think?
Ah, let's brew it off this is pretty soft. Okay Wow, it's Inger the second of frame
You see even pose maybe we can yeah, don't add all
Points to
Pose at least
Yeah, so we don't say that all the points out relation graph or pose cuz I propose optimizers taking time
Well, yeah, I mean so we can look into work
So I was doing this like clever thing where they like keep track of like which frames are likely the points to be found in
We can do the same thing
Well good look that's your jacking those points so good
Well, that's a lot of this a lot of features. Are that cinema?
Oh, yeah search by projection quality that you can't do that with or begin search by projection
a bomb at cinema
Alright so it can scale better with that
Down sample or points that are super close together. I already do that
I don't think you want you want you want to make the map less dense? I don't think we want to do that
Like I don't think that's the problem we're not getting look we're not getting that many matches
I'm actually printing out that I'm a matches for getting somebody's might just be a lot of matches but
Yeah, I mean, I think the problem is just the work of the love-u-lator they go bad look at that cinema
Use a higher resolution video there's a good drive through, New York
What's the license on us
It's long, hey, I'm happy to try a different video, but there's a few things that it can have
So this might have cuts the can of cuts it has to be Creative Commons license that it has to be relatively short
However, this doesn't have cots. Oh
Man but like this is a busy environment
Which is gonna make
Geo hot doesn't do shit, he's dead. My name is punk Reese I coach slam on the internet
And then I want to push on the density of his slant
All right
Like I wanted to after you get this to work what I really want to happen because I want this to do like a dense
surfing
I want to do like dense surface reconstruction. So it's like a super dense slam
What's the license on it, is it long enough that's too long
I mean like a two-minute Creative Commons license video and we could try it right now
We're gonna work at 10 today a shower still 200
Yeah, let's listen to sell out by real big fish, yeah
Spotify has a great song
Turn the radio off 96 bro ahead of their time
Dan twitch copyright strikes
The points are brutally guns here
Yeah, someone post a video in chat post a video in Chapel Thai slam on
That solid map right there, come on guys, give me a video
Why my type on this keyboard for this screen
Yo guys remember when we were at bugger King Ricky's all way back here
Can I slice them I guess I could
What
Control
Gonna give me a real video
We should be able to map Ohio in a reasonable time about this is unreasonably slow
Fast and slam. Well, like work Slim's like using threads and stuff which is kind of cheating
We're at density dance
Gap yeah, I guess I see
All right, fine I'll do it with you guys
I
Watched chess minions bear sits next to guy
Should you do this line?
There's too much motion
Come on bear I'm waiting for you
Creative commons standard youtube license
Creative Commons is better
Our Tony was gonna sit in the chair. Oh, that's a letdown
Ooh the immortal work left that looks do they get to watch I
Thought the bear was gonna sit in the chair, okay. I'm just I'm left out
Hi, this looks pretty good no
The embarrass how bad I am
On my media, oh, oh that's a lofty that's a lofty way to describe what that is media
No, you got a belches
Well, I'm not patient enough to play like long time control games. I'm better a long time control games. I
Played 10 minute
All right. Oh, we got 44 people right? Let's let's watch see if we find a short NYC driving video short
Five minutes of driving in New York City. Okay, and it's a oh
I love that fake news tow. Look at that. It's not five minutes
All right, so that guy yup. Just that was the red light. I'm sure yep. Good job, bro
Watch this at high speed
This is a good video
Well that got ya yeah, I've got a nice nice your turn bro
All right, well it's gonna detect all the features on that shit up and then this gets like sped up weird way, okay
So good. That's these are good things for a slam to the fact that this one looks good
This is too long. It's gonna take the wall
We'll try this one video and then we're out
Um download one moment please. We're going we're going with the dual pronged attack. Yeah
Wow, that's a long video damn you got stuck in a lot of traffic, bro
What
Don't do speedy
YouTube like break this stuff
Well convert I oh oh, okay is this one gonna work
Whose terrible this isn't that Creative Commons. Yeah it is
Striped video quality
Come on bro. Oh my Adobe Flash is out of date. Oh, that's great. Oh, oh, thanks Oh
Starting conversion. Oh, that's like quality start. Yeah zero. Oh,
Look look this is exciting
Use that oh that's nice like github downloader I trust that more
NES hosts on github. I trust wait. What is this shit? I
Hope it runs on my computer. Oh, that's sketch. Oh
Yeah, oh they got this we got this we got this is 100% 100% bro
But my ohio map is still being made
So good
Failed oh
Well now yep flash, okay, this is a scam
It's just a scam
This is terrible, I'm gonna know my URL once
It's gonna work
We have not authorized save video comm
Should I just get youtube-dl
Wait what okay
All right, what is this you took the other thing let's say
All right, whatever I'm sure it's not that sketchy
I'll the ad but I'll not turn off my ID blocker. I'll just install that I let's go
Yeah, I feel okay cool it was a YouTube D ality
Paste in the video name. Oh, sorry Wow. Okay. That was bad. I all controlled my
I'm tired this morning. I live in the closet
No, no, oh this looks like quality. Oh, yeah. Oh you tube DL you bros know what up?
Alright, you took the elbows coming through. Alright, what is it?
Videos I call the videos tests are tests iyc
Okay, so our beautiful map Ohio is still being made we are gonna control see this and let's try on NYC
Brand new video. I look at the quality look
At that quality, oh look at that building my focal length is clearly wrong
My focal point is wrong, that's why oh damn pretty good right I like this video cuz it has a turn
Youtube-dl we're gonna be using that in the future
Let's say, alright, let's make that turn let's go turn bro
All these feature they don't get a lot of features. It's a pretty nice map. I
Mean no, I shit. Let's massively skewed. I think my phone buoyant is wrong. Oh no, look what it is
Oh look at the barrel distortion on the website
But everything on the camera I look at a barrel barrel distortion Bros and of that
Let's see if it's gonna work on the turn
Won't work on the turn. I don't know. I don't know twitch slams not really been tested on turns before
He doesn't make a turn here, right
House is too slow. This is egregiously slow tomorrow speed guys. I
Know I'm getting worms on the texts, but it's good. It's rejecting them
Or it's saying are at infinity which I mean it's kind of stupid and it's gonna be annoying if we try to get rotation
Actually, they're uh, they're black. So it means that I've been used
Good a good twitch slam good twitch slam
Alright come on turn who's excited for the turn. Are you gonna turn here? I thought it turns here
Well, that's the guy who runs through the green light
Yeah, it only uses one car
The GPU I mean we can try using the GPU plus a little it's tomorrow
We'll profile and figure out what's slow we'll figure out a breakdown of the time
And we'll think about using the GPU. I don't know really GPU for like is it the optimizer? That's slow?
I just don't like the Python II crap. Yeah, I know. I'm sorry. I'm sorry
You guys I'm poor donate donate to my twitch stream so I could buy a new computer
Twitch lab hi. Come on make it turn its gonna turn bros. You think the turns gonna work?
Yeah, give it I give it a good 30% chance of working good
All right, you see how if we slowed down you feel like there was a lot of speed there and then we slow down
Slow and the old friends are really dense. So when I using or if slim uses keyframes, we're not using keyframing strategy
We're at you're just putting every frame in there
Which I kind of like I don't really like that giddyup keyframes because the new things not like optimized perfectly
Sure epsilon has good reasons for keyframes, but I don't really like them. Oh look. Look is that turning is that turning? What up?
I think it's turning. Oh
My god, this is horrendously slow. Yeah. Yeah could be I wasn't a twitch thought I'm gonna be a twitch stop
Smashed it up a pun. Yeah, hit that subscribe. You can't even subscribe. I don't know why I can't subscribe but apparently can't
Because I didn't like sign up to be a twitch
affiliate or whatever I
Don't know man, the world is full of scam you just seem so scammy like a twitch affiliate
It's still funny I agreed that a bit which stop don't get twitch not what do they do?
I should watch them twitch that themes and do what they do
And see if it works for me and when it doesn't work for me, I'll scream about sexism that always works. Oh
It's turning it's turning at a very slow. Oh my god. Okay. That was the worst turn I've ever seen
Well, I think it's a few things. I think my vocal is wrong
I mean that was a 90-degree turn and twitch slam turned a whole twenty degrees
Put my leg on my chair
I'm not do I look like any of those people man? I don't know why you think I'm anything like those people
Bill Gates Steve Jobs
Steve Wozniak, I'm not just not like those people man. I
Don't who that is, maybe I'm like that guy
Well, okay like it kind of made a turn alright
Well, we call that you know what this is undie bugga ball until we make trip slam fast. I
Know I know it's horrendous. Alright guys tomorrow
Today we fixed bugs
Tomorrow we make speed. What do you think? Look it made a good map until it made a turn
Oh, it's so good until it turned. I
Need to learn for the best dreamers, right if I like I'll keep eye mantle. Oh
Yeah, who's this twitch trending? Maybe a copyright strike for us. She's pretty
Can't buy things off her wish list
No, that's not my day I
Really don't get along with this girl don't click on every link you see I love clicking links browse
What Wow it's a nice chair I
Know
Oh, I I closed out the chat guys I closed out the chat I matki
Feud so sorry about that Matt key Q but I think that means that I am out for the day
That's it. That's a stream - I'll make things fast about mariachis